Guide to the Yale Student Papers Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Yale student essay collection, 1840-1990; Accession 19ND-A-381
  - Kwok, Danny W. Y. "Science in Communist China: Some Aspects of its Organization and Application" 34 pp, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 140)
  - Hulbert, Ellerd "The Academy of Sciences of the U.S.S.R." 40 pp, undated (Box 13, Folder 141)
  - Hess, Robert L. "Italian Colonial Policy in Somaliland, 1889-1935" 11 pp, undated (Box 13, Folder 142)
  - Havermeyer, H. W., Y.1952, Anderson, F. S., Y.1952, Curtis, C.B., Y.1957, and Lawrence, D.B. 1951 "The Atomic Energy industry of the United States" 60 pp (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - Gelband, Stephen; Douglas Johnson & Leonard Sperry "The History of the American Life Tables" 23 pp, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Gerstle; J. T., Y.1957 and G. A. Durrant des Aulnois, Y.1957 "French Life Tables" 18 pp (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - Fry, Nenah "The Changing Cultural Pattern in the Gold Coast and Nigeria as Influenced by Modern Science" 61 pp, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Danforth, G. H. "Factors in the Growth of Religious Toleration" 21 pp, undated (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Cross, Barbara M. "The Church and the Repression of Medieval Heresy" 18 pp, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Jackson, Dorothy "The Interactions of Religion, Education, and Science in India Today" 90 pp, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Crane, R. I. "The Sociology of Knowledge: an Exposition" 53 pp, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Fang, C. Y. "Some Remarks of [sic] the Modernization of the Chinese Language (Lo-Cheng-Fu)" 165 pp, undated (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Wight, Charles H. C. "Time is of the Essence" 16 pp, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - Johnson, Reid B. "All the Sad Young Men: a study of the American Novelists of the 1950s" 25 pp, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - Slater, James H., Y.1946 "The Concept of Liberty as it evolved through the Bill of Rights" 46 pp (Box 14, Folder 154)
  - Sewell, Gilbert "The Development of Psychology, Biology and Medicine from 1830 to 1860" 35 pp, undated (Box 14, Folder 155)
  - Masters, Charles D. Y.1957 "Life Tables in Spanish-speaking Countries" 8 pp (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - Liddell, W. "The Science of Signs" 49 pp, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 159)
  - Lesher, Robert G "A History of Geology as Related to the History of Science and Society" 64 pp, undated (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - Raths, James "Topics in Mathematics and Physics, 1830-1860" 25 pp, undated (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - Ponvert, Antonio, Jr. Y.1958 "The Korean Conflict and the Captive Mind" 25 pp (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - Kaplan, Lawrence S. "The Influence of Science upon Modern Imperialism, 1870-1914" 45 pp, undated (Box 14, Folder 163)
  - Kirkland, Edward C. "Men, Cities and Transportation in New England: A History, 1820-1900" 75 pp, undated (Box 14, Folder 164)
  - Rouch, Jonathan C. Y. 1982 "The Transformation of Geology: British Earth Science between Hutton and Lyell, 1779 - 1830" Joint first prize of the Andrew D. White Prize. 66 pp. (Box 15, Folder 167)
  - Larkin, John Y. 1954 "Unionism at Yale" 116 pp. (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - McGerr, Michael E. Y.1976 "The Conflict Over Economic Expansion: A Study in the Politics of the Tariff in the Gilded Age" 94 pp (Box 15, Folder 170)
  - Farrar, Cynthia Y.1976 "The Rule of Reason in Thucydides" 87 PP (Box 15, Folder 171)
  - Fallon, Richard [Y. 1974?] "Toward a New Center: Alfred Bingham and Walter Lippmann in the New Deal Era" 115 pp, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 172)
  - Naftali, Timothy J. Y.1983 "Yale Ph.D., O.S.S., C.I.A.: Sherman Kent, Norman Holmes Pearson, and the Development of an American Intelligence Profession" Winner of the John Addison Porter Prize in American History for Juniors and Seniors 74 pp (Box 15, Folder 173)
  - Callpott, W. Hardy Y.1983 "The Transition from Roman to Anglo-Saxon in Britain: The Dark Ages in the Upper Thames Basin, 400-600 A.D." Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize for Juniors or Seniors in European History. 93 pp (Box 15, Folder 174)
  - Gander, Todd Y.1985 "The Evolution of the Magna Carts" Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History 18 pp, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 175)
  - Freeman, Bob Y.1985 "Benjamin Franklin and the Stamp Act Crisis" Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in American History 118 pp, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 176)
  - Sweder, Betsy Y.1983 "Taiping & Tiluan (Heavenly Peace & Earthly Troubles): The Experiences of a Baptist Missionary in Shanghai 1864" Robert Cries Prize 60 pp (Box 15, Folder 177)
  - Goldsworthy, Thomas "Social Control and Conservative Reform: Elites and the Park Movement in New Haven 1880-1905" 40 pp 4 maps, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 178)
  - Reilly, Thomas Y.1979 "The Evolution of Paternalism at Yale College" 57 pp (Box 16, Folder 179)
  - Osterweis, Rollin G. "The Influence of the Code Napoléon on the French Family Unit" 20 pp, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 180)
  - McLellan, Bob Y.1973 "The Institutional Phenomenon: a Socio-Economic Inquiry" 146 pp (Box 16, Folder 181)
  - Adams, Alexander B. Y.1939 "Ben Jonson" 19 pp., [ca. 1936] (Box 16, Folder 182)
  - Adams, Alexander B. Y.1939 "A Comparison of Thomas Carlyle's French Revolution with Charles Dicken's Tale of Two Cities" 17 pp., 1936 (Box 16, Folder 183)
  - Adams, Alexander B. Y.1939 "Tristan and Isolt" 16 pp., 1936 (Box 16, Folder 184)
  - Horenstein, Richard B. Y.1986 "The Failure of Scientific Education and the Decline of Economic Competitiveness in Britain from the Chrystal Palace to World War I" Andrew D. White Prize for Freshmen & Sophomores in European History, 19 pp., 1984 (Box 16, Folder 185)
  - Hofheinz, Paul Y.1984 "W. Averell Harriman and the Soviet Concessions Policy" Joint winner - John Addison Porter Prize in American History for Juniors & Seniors, 65 pp. (Box 16, Folder 186)
  - Duff, Sarah U. Y.1984 "An Opportunity Lost: Ike's Disarmament Gate Remains Shut" Joint Winner John Addison Porter Prize in American History for Juniors and Seniors, 94 pp. (Box 16, Folder 187)
  - Markel, Douglas C. Y.1984 "Yale-in-China 1923-1927: A Case History of Chinese Nationalism Confronting the Foreign Missionary Education Movement" The Robert D. Gries Prize for an essay on any part of the world except Europe and the U.S. 102 pp. (Box 16, Folder 188)
  - Barnes, David S. Y.1984 "Change and Continuity in the "Transformation" of Central Paris: The Arts - et - Metiers Neighborhood in the mid-19th Century" Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize for Juniors and Seniors in European History 133 pp. (Box 16, Folder 189)
  - Fritz, Emanuel 1914f "Planting Plan for the Racebrook Tract of the New Haven Water Company," 72 pp., 1913 (Box 17, Folder 190)
  - Kiang, Lindsey "A Withdrawal to Greatness: The Life of Kan-Ichi Asakawa" 45 pp., 1964 (Box 17, Folder 191)
  - Yustak, Laura Ann Y.1984 "Cambrai, France: The German Occupation, World War I" 72 pp. (Box 17, Folder 192)
  - Isenberg, Alison "Fanny Goodridge Cheever; A Missionary of the New England Spirit in the Nineteenth Century American West." 47 pp/, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 193)
  - Henkin, David M. Y. (1987), "The Working Men's Party of 1829: a Radical Experiment in New York City" 21pp., 1984 December (Box 17, Folder 195)
    - Winner of the Andrew D. White prize in American History for a Freshman or Sophomore, 1985
  - Meyer, Jeffrey. Y. 1985 "Politics & Planning in a Small American City: the Public Housing Program in Mount Vernon, N.Y. 1934-1950," 65 pp, Winner of the John Addison Porter prize in American History for Juniors & Seniors (Box 17, Folder 196)
  - Kamensky, Jane Y. 1985 "Limits of Resistance; The Uncertain Legacy of Ernst Von Weizsacker & the Final Solution" 58 pp. Joint first prize winner of the Andrew D. White Prize for Juniors & Seniors in European History (Box 17, Folder 197)
  - Baker, Ruth: Y. 1985 "The Saint & Society: An Elusive Integration." A Study of St. Catherine of Siena. 43 pp. Joint first prize winner of the Andrew D. White Prize for Juniors & Seniors in European History (Box 17, Folder 198)
  - Riker, Howard J. Y. 1987 "A Place of One's Own: Stature and Mercantile Coffee House in 17th & 18th Century England." 18 pp. Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History for Freshman and Sophomores, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 199)
  - Kuo, Peggy Y. 1985 "Preaching to the 'Yeller-dogs': An American Baptist Missionary in China" 59 pp. Winner of the Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 17, Folder 200)
  - Lamar, Susan K. Y. 1985 "A Pioneering Venture in Nursing Education: The Connecticut Training School for Nurses" 72 pp. (Box 17, Folder 201)
  - Hanson, R. Scott Y. 1985 "C.-E.-A Winslow and the Reorganization of Connecticut's Public Health System" 95 pp. (Box 17, Folder 202)
  - Simon, David J. Y. 1985 "At Our Feet: The Yale Conservation Program 1950-1960" 52 pp., 1985 April (Box 17, Folder 203)
  - Salzman, James Y. 1985 "Jews Fight for the Right to Fight: The Committee for a Jewish Army 1941-1943" 78 pp., 1985 April (Box 17, Folder 204)
  - Sargeant, Kimon Y. 1985 "Driven to Drink: The Crusading Impulse of Irving Fisher" 45 pp. (Box 18, Folder 205)
  - Chin, Stephen Y. 1986 "The Vans Controversy; A. Mighty Stir About a Most Trivial Matter" 73pp. (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - Greenway, Alice Y. 1986 "Life and Female Solidarity in the Sisterhoods of Rural Guang Dong: A Case Study of Pin Wong" 62 pp. Winner of the R. D. Cries Prize (Box 18, Folder 207)
  - Grossman, Lewis Y. 1986 "The Movement to Found an American National University in the Early Years of the Republic" 68 pp Winner of the K. K. Walker Prize (Box 18, Folder 208)
  - Bromberg, Daniel Y. 1986 "Fernando Wood: A Practical Politician in the Civil War Era" 76 pp. Winner of the Porter Prize (Box 18, Folder 209)
  - Weinberger, Eric Y. 1989 "Popular Radicalism in the Civil War: the Clubmen and Levellers" 11 pp. Winner of the A. D. White Prize, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 210)
  - Linninger, Tom Y. 1988 "Biracial Cooperation in the Southern Tenant Farmers Union" 22 pp. Winner of the A. D. White Prize, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 211)
  - Marine, Joseph Y. 1986 "When Foreign Policy Collides with Conscience: the Boston Five Conspiracy Trial" 102 pp. Winner of the J. A. Porter Prize (Box 18, Folder 212)
  - Boasberg, Tom Y. 1986 "The Solution Fails: The Creation and Collapse of the Northern Ireland Executive" 81 pp. W. Sturley Second Prize (Box 18, Folder 213)
  - Smith, Scott Y. 1986 "The Kadets and the Polish Question 1905-1917: A Study in Liberal Imperialism" 69 pp. Winner of the A. D. White Prize (Box 18, Folder 214)
  - Henkin, David Michel Y. 1987 "The Slavery of Right and the Slavery of Want" 45 pp. Winner of the John Addison Porter Prize First Prize (Box 18, Folder 215)
  - Lane, Steven G. Y. 1987 "Wales and the March in Royal Policy, 1217-1258" 77 pp. Winner of the Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 18, Folder 217)
  - Barr, Michael S. Y. 1987 "To Sing of Africa: The Black Consciousness Movement in South Africa, 1969-1977" 76 pp. Winner of the Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 19, Folder 218)
  - Crystal, Catherine Robin Y. 1987 "Redefining Beatrice Webb: A and Socialist Attitude Toward Feminism Gender" 65 pp. Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize Joint First Prize (Box 19, Folder 219)
  - Cowan, Andy Y. 1987 "The Guerrilla War Against Franco" 71 pp. Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize Joint First Prize (Box 19, Folder 220)
  - Beals, Katherine Pier Y. 1987 "Demands from the Allies & the Soviet Option" 77 pp. Winner of the Hajo Holborn Prize (Box 19, Folder 221)
  - Boudett, Michael Y. 1988 "Legislating Frontiers: The Passage of the Newlands Reclamation Act of 1902" 31 pp. First Place Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in American History, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 222)
  - Bylinsky, Greg Y. 1988 "The Colorado Mines, 1900-1914" 24 pp. Second Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in American History, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 223)
  - Najarian, James Y. 1988 "Women's Issues and the Fate of the Weather Underground" 25 pp. Third Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in the American History, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 224)
  - Levine, Peter Y. 1989 "The Objective Perspective: Art and Philosophy in the Age of Boethius" 22 pp. First Place Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 225)
  - Kutz, Chris Y. 1989 "The Politics of the Policraticus: The Concept of Freedom in John of Salisbury" 13 pp. Second Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 226)
  - Milkes, Elisa Y. 1988 "Absolutism under Louis XIV: An Enlightend Perspective" 9 pp. Third Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 227)
  - Le Tran, Thang Y.1988 "John Collier and the Indians in the Making of the Indian Reorganization Act" 64 pp. (Box 19, Folder 228)
  - Fu, Paul Y. Y. 1989 "Chinatown: The 'Great Wall' in America" 40 pp. First Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in American History, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 229)
  - Boss, Julia Y. 1989 "Seattle and Alaska: Transportation, Trade and Travellers. City-Hinterland Relationships, 1897-1910" 35 pp. Second Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in American History, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 230)
  - Carrier, Michael Y. 1991 "Spanish Decline and American Treasure: Was Earl J. Hamilton Right?" 14 pp. First Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in American History, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 231)
  - Dekle, Catherine Y. 1989 "Asquith and His Cabinet, 1908-1914" 26 pp. Second Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 232)
  - Silbiger, Andrew Y. 1989 "Upstairs, Downstairs: A Study of Stratification in Nineteenth Century British Society" 35 pp. Second Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 233)
  - Milkes, Elisa Y. 1989 "The Legacy of Sinn Fein: Non-Violent Change, Republic Voice, Shattered Unity" 16 pp. Second Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 234)
  - Paci, Myra Y. 1988 "Janet Flanner & Her Circle: Women in Paris between the Wars" 63 pp. First Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History (Box 19, Folder 235)
  - Klerman, Daniel Y. 1988 "Pater and Puber: The Legal Regulation of the Relationship between Fathers and Older Children" 51 pp. First Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History (Box 19, Folder 236)
  - Singer, Daniel Y. 1988 "Merchant Piety: A Study of the Life and Literature of Goro Dati" 78 pp. First Prize Winner of the Andrew D. White Prize in European History (Box 20, Folder 237)
  - Gripkey, Stephen Y. 1988 "John Stuart Mill's Three Essays on Religion: A Culmination of his prior thought, with possible influence from Unitarianism" 63 pp. First Prize Winner of the Winifred Sturley Prize in English History (Box 20, Folder 238)
  - Lelewer, Stephen Y. 1988 "Order Versus Progress: Frederic Harrison and the Legalization of British Trade Unions, 1861-1874" 66 pp. Second Prize Winner of the Winifred Sturley Prize in English History (Box 20, Folder 239)
  - Sachs, Jennifer Y. 1988 "In the Welfare of Zion: Mormon Women's Responses to Plural Marriage" 52 pp. First Prize Winner of the John Addison Porter Prize in American History (Box 20, Folder 240)
  - Meyer, Charles G. Y. 1988 "From Great Awakening to Revolution: The New Light Party in Colonial Connecticut" 72 pp. Third Prize Winner of the John Addison Porter Prize in American History (Box 20, Folder 241)
  - Rider, Joshua S. Y. 1988 "United States Military Planning and the Crisis in Azerbaijan, 1946" 59 pp. Third Prize Winner of the John Addison Porter Prize in American History (Box 20, Folder 242)
  - Haralson, Rebeca Galvez Y. 1988 "The Guatemalan Agrarian Reform of 1952 and Rural Political Mobilization" 70 pp. Winner of the Robert D. Gries Prize for an essay on any part of the world excepting Europe and the United States (Box 20, Folder 243)
  - Hussain, Nasser Y. 1988 "Identity Formation and the End of Colonialism: Iabal, Jinnah, and the formation of Indian Muslim Identity" 62 pp. Winner of the Robert D. Gries Prize for an essay on any part of the world excepting Europe and the United States (Box 20, Folder 244)
  - Kihn, Paul Y. 1988 "Ambiguous Participation: The Fragile Realm of African Teachers in South Africa" 90 pp. Winner of the Robert D. Gries Prize for an essay on any part of the world excepting Europe and the United States (Box 20, Folder 245)
  - Marchese, Steven Y. 1988 "Paesani on the Pacific: Italian Immigration and Settlement in Northern California, 1880-1920" 57 pp. First Prize Winner of the Katherine K. Walker Prize (Box 20, Folder 246)
  - McCurry, Charles "Urban Society and the Church: Medieval Metz, ca. 1200-1378" Unfinished dissertation because of the death of the author. 385pp., 1985 (Box 20, Folder 247)
  - Lawrence, Katherine A. "Between the Lines" Videotape, 100 min., 1990 (Box 21, Folder 248)
  - Clark, Cullum Y. 1989 "The Transformation of the Naval Balance of Power and the Coming of War in the Pacific, 1939-1941" 84 pp. Joint First Prize - John Addison Porter Prize (Box 21, Folder 249)
  - Johnson, Carina Y. 1989 "'No Lesse Wonderful Then Most True': The Testimony of Children Against Their Parents in Elizabethan and Early Stuart Witchcraft Trials" 50 pp. Second Prize Winner: Winifred Sturley Prize. (Box 21, Folder 250)
  - Philbin, Patrick Y. 1989 "The Edwardian Conquest of Wales" 76 pp. First Prize Winner: Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 21, Folder 251)
  - Hyson, Jeffrey Y. 1989 "'Some Great and Capital Change': The Image of Valley Forge in the American Historical Consciousness" 69 pp. Winner of the Kathryn F. Walker Prize. (Box 21, Folder 252)
  - Kenna Roger Y. 1989 "Nationalism Co-opted: The Arab Revolt, T.E. Lawrence and British Imperialism, 1916-1921" 63 pp. Winner of the Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 21, Folder 253)
  - Eisenach, Emily Y. 1989 "Secular Magistrates and Witchcraft Belief in Early Sixteenth Century European Witchcraft Trials" 58 pp. Joint First Prize Winner: Andrew D. White Prize. (Box 21, Folder 254)
  - Esty, Joshua D. Y. 1989 "Kingdom of Hope and Failure: Western Views of China in the Decade of Disillusionment" 63 pp. Joint First Prize Winner: Andrew D. White Prize (Box 21, Folder 255)
  - Carpenter, Dale Allen Y. 1989 "Revisiting Griswold: An Exploration of its Political, Social and Legal Origins" 72 pp. Joint First Prize Winner: John Addison Porter Prize (Box 21, Folder 256)
  - Franklin, David Y. 1990 From Jews to Men: the Abbe Gregoire and the Rhetoric of Revolutionary Regeneration" 57 pp. Joint First Prize Winner: Andrew D. White Prize (Box 21, Folder 257)
  - Roff, Sarah Y. 1990 "National 'Socialism' in Berlin, 1926-1932: The Labor Tactics of the SA and the NSBO in the 'Stronghold of Marxism" 65 pp. Joint First Prize Winner: Andrew D. White Prize (Box 21, Folder 258)
  - Simes, Jeffrey Alan Y. 1990 "The Great Shelter Debate: The Fall of American Civil Defense, 1961-1962" 76 pp. Joint First Prize Winner: John Addison Porter Prize (Box 22, Folder 259)
  - McCarren, Mark Joseph Y. 1990 "The Scientific Contributions of Othniel Charles Marsh: Birds, Bones and Brontotheres" 64 pp. Joint First Prize Winner: John Addison Porter Prize (Box 22, Folder 260)
  - Chapin, Nicole T. Y. 1990 "Beyond the Models of Missionaries and Men: A Look at the History of Chinese Education for Women in the Early Twentieth Century on Its Own Terms" 59 pp. Winner of the Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 22, Folder 262)
  - Panner, Daniel Y. 1990 "Times of Temptation': Massachusetts During the English Civil War" 59 pp. Winner of the Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 22, Folder 263)
  - Greenberg, David Y. 1990 "Peace and Quiet: How Richard Nixon Silenced the Antiwar Movement" 69pp. Winner of the Kathryn K. Walker Prize (Box 22, Folder 264)
  - Grant, Justus Herbert Y. 1870's "Permanent Way", 1970 (Box 22, Folder 265)
  - Pimsleur, Julie Y. 1990 "Boola Boola….Yale Goes Coed" video (60 min.) (Box 22, Folder 266)
  - Childs, A.H. Y.1861 "Diversity of Conditions Among Men" and "Influences of Trials on Men of Genius", 1858 (Box 22, Folder 268)
  - Ballard, Elizabeth (1940 Ph.D.) "Dipolar Ions", circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 269)
  - Renzie, Vincent R. Y. 1985 & David J. Hyder "A Collection of Documentation of My Youth in Literature or the Scrap Book", 1984 (Box 23)
  - Pimsleur, Julie Y. (1990), "Boola Boola....Yale Goes Coed," videotape (VHS), 60 min (Box 24)
    - Use copy, 60 min, 1 (Box 24U)
- Collection of compositions, Yale College Classes of 1855-1857, Accession 19ND-A-388
  - Class of 1855
    - A-J, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - K-W, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Class of 1856
    - A-K, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - L-W, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Class of 1857 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Student essays in American Studies, 1950-1978; Accession 19ND-A-437
  - Alegi, Peter C. "A History of Catholicism at Yale to 1943" 145 pp., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allen, Frederick Warner "The Adoption of Standard Time in 1883" 155 pp., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anderson, Margaret E. "The Flapper Unwrapped" 135 pp., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arditi, Ralph "Throbbing Between Two Lives: Patterns of Freedom in Four American Novels" 183 pp., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bailey, Guy B. "Career of a 'New Southerner': Joel Chandler Harris" 99 pp., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bannister, Robert C., Jr. "Massachusetts and the Mininum Wage" 97 pp., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bannon, Timothy F. "When a Black Man Writes a Book: James Weldon Johnson and the Concept of Culture" 134 pp., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bates, Benjamin "Black Community Life 1865-1920" 125 pp., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Berenblum, Marvin "Democratization of Labor Unions" 143 pp., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Berk, Dennis "Victor Berger: The Practical Idealist" 263 pp., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Berkson, H. Neil "Elements of University Growth 1870-1910" 95 pp., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Betts, Roland W. "Besieged Showpiece in the Promised Land" 168 pp., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Beynart, R.W. "The Anti-Rent Policy in New York State Politics - 1844-1846" 181 pp., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bing, John "Deerfield Integration" 90 pp., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Blatchford, E.W. "The Style and Sense of E.B. White in The New Yorker 1925-1950" 139 pp., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bonner, Dan E., Jr. "Disfranchisement of the East Texas Black Community: 1821-1954 209 pp., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Booher, Stephen R. "The Story of the Federal Writers' Project: A Case Study of a Work-Relief Experiment" 161 pp., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bosse, M.J. "A Study of Deere and Company in Its Relation to Moline, Illinois" 110 pp., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Brown, Byrd H. "Richard Wright" 168 pp., 1951 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Buccino, Robert A. "The Catholic Reaction to Progressive Education"(for Porter Prize) 146 pp., 1959 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Buchman, Arnold E. "Contemporary American Attitudes Toward Law as Reflected in Current American Fiction" 89 pp., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Bynack, Vincent P. "Pennsylvania in Crisis" 164 pp., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Cavallon, Michael F. "The New Haven and Northampton Canal, 1822-1847" 115 pp., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Clark, Peter L. "Walter Lippman's Theories of the Citizen 1908-1925" 76 pp., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Connery, Robert T. "Fisher Ames" 163 pp., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Conrad, Winthrop Brown, Jr. "Rehearsal for Redemption" 112 pp., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Cosgrove, Thomas F., Jr. "Malden, Massachusetts: Microcosm of the American Experience" 157 pp., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Costello, Jan Clifford "The Crisis of Old Age in America" 115 pp., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Cowan, Michael H. "The Boy Scouts of America and the Protestant Church" 188 pp., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Craig, Marshall W. "Progressive America and the Russian Mirror" 82 pp., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 33)